Joel Martin Halpern collection
American Folklife Center, Library of Congress
- Series 1: Eastern European materials, 1870-1999
  - Subseries 1: Manuscript materials, 1915-1998, Dates in this series usually refer to publication dates; the collection contains many photocopies of publications, with some originals.
    - Publications by other authors categorized by language, 1915-1998
      - English
        - Vlahovic, Mitar S, and Bosiljka Radovc, National Costumes of Serbia, in the Ethnographic Museum in Belgrade. Belgrade: Jugosavija, 1954, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 7/81)
        - Sobic, Jerina. Costumes and Ornaments, in the Ethnographic Museum in Belgrade. Beograd: Jugoslavija, 1956, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 7/82)
        - Vlahovic, Mitar S., and Bosiljka Radovic. Popular Costumes of the XIX Century, in the Ethnographic Museum of Beograd. Beograd: The Ethnographical Museum, Beograd, 1958, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 7/83)
        - Stankiewicz, Edward. Grammatical Neutralization in Slavic Expressive Forms. London: William Clowes and Sons. 1961. Reprint. Word 17, no. 2 (August, 1961): 128-45, 1961, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 7/84)
        - Stankiewicz, Edward. The Prosodic System of the Slovenian Declension: 257-66, 1968, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 7/85)
        - Bynum, David E. Themes of the Young Hero in Serbocroatian Oral Epic Tradition. PMLA 83, no 5: 1296-1303, 1968, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 7/86)
        - Stankiewicz, Edward. The Forms of the Infinitive in the South Slavic Languages. Richerche Slavistiche 17-19: 495-504, 1970-1972, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 7/87)
        - Georges, Robert A. Process and Structure in Traditional Storytelling in the Balkans: Some Preliminary Remarks. Aspects of the Balkans: Continuity and Change: 319-37, 1972, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 7/88)
        - Stankiewicz, Edward. The Accent and Grammatical Categories of the Stems in South Slavic: 193-202, 1973, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 7/89)
        - Doömötör, Tekla. Ritual Poetry-Ceremonial Songs in Eastern Europe. IXth International Congress of Anthropological and Ethnological Sciences: 14 pages, 1973, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 7/90)
        - Sokolova, V.K. Some Traditional Symbols in Slavonic Folk-Poetry. IXth International Congress of Anthropological and Ethnological Sciences: 17 pages, 1973, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 7/91)
        - Dreifus, Claudia. One Gold Coast Where a Dollar's Still a Dollar. Signature (March): 20-29, 52, 1974, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 7/92)
        - Leiberman, Robert. 'Vi, decko' or A Constructive Critique of Joel Martin Halpern's 'Serbian Village': 19 pages. Includes written comments from Barbara Kerewsky-Halpern's as well as correspondence from Barbara Kerewsky-Halpern to Robert Leiberman, 1975, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 7/93)
        - Radovic, Dusan. Let's Love Belgrade a Little More Each Day. Illustrated by Petricic, Dusan, translated by Čekanovic, Kolja. Belgrade: BIGZ, 1977, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 7/94)
        - Foley, John M. The Oral Singer in Context: Halil Bajoric, Guslar. 9 pages, 1977, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 7/95)
        - Pitchor, Miriam and Beverly Robinson. A Structural Approach to the Position of Women in the Ballads of Marko Kraljevic.: 30 pages. Barbara-Kerewsky Halpern's correspondence with Pitchor and comments on paper included, 1978, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 8/96)
        - Program from Festival of Yugoslavian Art: October 19-November 15, 1980, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 8/97)
        - The Thin Veneer: The Peoples of Bosnia and their Disappearing Cultural Heritage (Exhibition Catalogue). Amherst: University Gallery, University of Massachusetts (April 13-June 7, 1997): 16. The exhibition was guest curated by Walter Denny, Department of Art History, University of Massachusetts and Joel Martin Halpern, with the curatorial assistance of Roxanne Stanulis, 1997, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 8/98)
        - The 14th International Congress of Anthropological and Ethnological Sciences. Williamsburg, Virginia: William and Mary College. Program and abstracts, 1998, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 8/99)
        - Svetozar Markovic and the Socialist Movement. 14 pages; (Undated) The Development of Realism in Yugoslavia. 10 pages; (Undated) Serbian Realism 1870-1900. 15 pages; (Undated) The Development of the Novel in Serbia.: 15 pages; (Undated) Narodne pesme.: 13 pages; (Undated): The Seoska Pripovetka in Serbian Literature: 11 pages, undated, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 8/100)
        - Foley, John M. The Traditional Structure of Utterance in Ibro Basic's 'Alagic Alija and Velagic Selim,' 32 pages (Includes notes), undated, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 8/101)
        - Mladenovic, Zivomir. Unpublished Folk Poems of Vuk Karadzic. The Slavonic and East European Review: 372-85. Cambridge University Press. (reprint), undated, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 8/102)
        - Yugoslavia: 16 pages, undated, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 8/103)
      - French
        - Deuxième Congrès International des Etudes du Sud-Est Européen: Liste des Participants. (Fifth International Congress of Southeast European Studies, Athens, May 7-13): 61 pages, 1970, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 8/104)
        - Cinquième Congrès International des Etudes du Sud-Est Européen: Liste des Participants. (Fifth International Congress of Southeast European Studies, Belgrade, September 11-17): includes program 76 pages, and list of participants 36 pages, 1984, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 8/105)
        - Gjergji, Andromaqi. L'Ethnographie et le Village Albanais d'Aujourd'hui: 15 pages. (Paper given at Fifth Congress by Albanian delegation), 1984, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 8/106)
        - Zhivomir, Mladenovic. Quelques Traits Communs des Poèmes Epiques Serbocroats et Néo Grecs. Yougoslavie, undated, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 8/107)
      - German
        - Alte Volksmusikinstrumente Aus Ungarn. Budapest: Aus den Sammlungen des Ethnographischen Museums. 12 pages, 1985, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 9/108)
        - Hoffmann, Dr. Tamás. Zur ländlichen Möbel-und Wohnkultur Ungarns. Cloppenburg: Museumdorf Cloppenburg. 56 pages, 1987, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 9/109)
      - Macedonian, Selected titles translated into English
        - Folk Poems and Interpretations of South Slav Rhythm: 275-89, 1968, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 9/110)
      - Slovenian
        - Skofja Loka: 32 pages, undated, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 9/111)
      - Russian, Selected titles translated into English
        - Vasilisa Prekrasnaia: 12 pages, 1965, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 9/112)
        - Writing Poems: 11 pamphlets, undated, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 9/113)
      - Serbian, Selected titles translated into English
        - Malesevo and Maleseveci. (Macedonia): 462 pages, 1929, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 9/114)
        - Herbal Medicine: Regional uses and methods, spells and witchcraft: 35-42, 84-90, 117, 1931, 1933, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 9/115)
        - Hunting in Kolasinu: 71 pages, 1933, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 9/116)
        - Yugoslav Minorities in Europe: 139 pages, 1938, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 9/117)
        - Burmanska Union: 78 pages, 1954, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 9/118)
        - Narodne nosnje Jugoslavije, pt. I: Dalmacija, Bosna, Hercegovina: 17 pages, 1954, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 9/119)
        - Narodne nosnje Jugoslavije, pt. II: Serbija, Makedonija, Crnagora, Vojvodina: 18 pages, 1955, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 9/120)
        - Narodne nosnje Jugoslavije, pt. III: Hrvatska: 18 pages, 1956, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 9/121)
        - Ledi Pedzet: 18 pages, 1958, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 9/122)
        - Peasant Art from Kovavice: 69 pages, 1962, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 9/123)
        - Stankiewicz, Edward. Problemi Pesnikog Jezika s Gledista Lingvistike: 23-34, 1963, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 9/124)
        - Museum of the Party's Illegal Printing Office, Belgrade: 64 pages, 1966, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 9/125)
        - Foundation of Epic Poems: 309-48, 1968, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 9/126)
        - Spomen-zbirka Pavla Beljanskog (Book Collector): 35 pages, 1968, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 10/127)
        - The Best Elements in Classical Poems from Istanbul: 205-9, 1972, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 10/128)
        - Mladenovi, Zivomir. The Problem of Language Barriers in the Transmission of Folk Poetry from Zbornik, 18. Kongresa Sufj, Bovec 1971. Ljublana, 1973, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 10/129)
        - Manuscript of Folk Poems in 'Serbian Dictionary' from Zbornik, 18. Kongresa Sufj, Bovec 1971. Ljublana, 1973, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 10/130)
        - Slavic Conference (7 pamphlets), 1973-1975, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 10/131)
        - A Literature of Work as Speech Structure: 203-31, 1974, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 10/132)
        - Basma (about mythology, healing, and spells): 651, 1975, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 10/133)
        - Literary History: 5 issues, 1975-1977, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 10/134)
        - Expressions of Our Feelings in Our Traditional Epic Lyrics: 178-85, 1976, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 10/135)
        - Folk Costumes of Yugoslavia: 45 pages, plus photos, 1976, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 10/136)
        - Jovic, Dusan. Perspektive Sociolingvistike u Jugoslaviji. Jezik u Drustvenoj Sredini: 21-32, 1976, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 10/137)
        - Society for Upkeeping (Preservation of) Fiddle Music in Kikindia, (Vojvodina) memorial book: 159 pages, 1976, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 10/138)
        - The Study of National Poems Written in Ten Syllables: 511-39, 1976, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 10/139)
        - The Way to Write Poems in Ten Syllables: 224-30, 1976, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 10/140)
        - Veselo Zvontse: 109 pages, 1977, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 10/141)
        - Immigrants' Pad. (Serbian poems): 157 pages, 1981, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 10/142)
        - Yarn on the Moon. (Serbian folk works): 92 pages, 1981, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 10/143)
        - Poet's Newspaper: 48 pages, 1984, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 10/144)
        - Serbian paintings and sculptures; Serbian ethnofabrics; Serbian sculpture art (3 issues), 1987, 1988, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 10/145)
        - Village houses in the Kopaonik Mountains in Serbia: 90 pages, 1988, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 11/146)
        - Research on national musical instruments in Serbia. Belgrade: 48 pages, 1990, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 11/147)
        - The Best Elements in Contemporary Poems: 501-17, includes Barbara Kerewsky-Halpern's notes on article, undated, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 11/148)
        - History of Family Smodlaka XVIII to XX Century: 45 pages. Includes letter to Prof. Halpern from Dr. Smodlaka, undated, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 11/149)
        - Stankiewicz, Edward. Rec Nozve u `Hasanaginici: 95-7, undated, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 11/150)
        - Slovenska Kmecka Nosa (Peasant Costumes of Slovenia): 17 pages, 1966, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 11/151)
        - Slovenian Museum Regional Study: 17 pages, 1966, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 11/152)
        - The Genealogy of Turin and Franco: 129 pages, 1969, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 11/153)
        - Slavonski Zlatovez: 5 pages, 1977, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 11/154)
        - Glasnik: Bulletin of Slovene Ethnological Society: 104 pages, 1991, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 11/155)
        - Bagdala, Poetry, and Literature, 1973, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 17/173 (Oversize))
  - Subseries 2: Sound recordings, 1954-1986, For Joel Martin Halpern's notes concerning these recordings, please see Box-Folder 1/6 entitled "Tape Log and Inventory."
    Intentional gap in numbers
    - Reel-to-reel tapes
      - Udovica Jana (The Widow Ana), 1954, AFC 1998/001: SR003; 1 reel-to-reel tape (7 inch)
        Recorded in Orasac, Serbia. Transcribed and published as an article by Barbara Halpern in Slavonic Review.
      - Folksongs in Orasac, Serbia, 1954, AFC 1998/001: SR004; U.S. Information Service in Belgrade; 1 reel-to-reel tape (7 inch)
      - Folksongs in Orasac, Serbia, 1954, AFC 1998/001: SR005; U.S. Information Service in Belgrade; 1 reel-to-reel tape (7 inch)
      - The Halperns in Voice of America interview on Yugoslavia, 1955, AFC 1998/001: SR006; 1 reel-to-reel tape (7 inch)
        Interview conducted in New York for broadcast to Yugoslavia; experiences in Yugoslavia by Barbara Halpern and Joel Martin Halpern, 1953-54.
      - Interview with Gena Fine, 1965, AFC 1998/001: SR018; 1 reel-to-reel tape (7 inch); See transcript
        Interview conducted in Waltham, Massachusetts. Discusses her life in a Serbian village, gender division of roles, experiences at a peasant market.
      - Interview with Gena Fine about Serbian village life, AFC 1998/001: SR019; 1 reel-to-reel tape (7 inch)
        Continued from 1965. Includes transcript.
      - Barbara Kerewsky-Halpern's interviews in Orasac, Serbia, 1975, AFC 1998/001: SR020; 1 reel-to-reel tape (5 inch)
      - Joel Martin Halpern interviewing in Orasac, Serbia, 1975, AFC 1998/001: SR021; 1 reel-to-reel tape (5 inch)
      - Joel Martin Halpern interviewing old men in Orasac, Serbia, 1975, AFC 1998/001: SR022; 1 reel-to-reel tape (5 inch)
      - Barbara Halpern and Joel Martin Halpern interviewing in Orasac, Serbia, 1975, AFC 1998/001: SR023; 1 reel-to-reel tape (5 inch)
      - Joel Martin Halpern interviewing old man in Orasac, Serbia, 1975, AFC 1998/001: SR024; 1 reel-to-reel tape (5 inch)
      - Barbara Halpern interviewing in Orasac, Serbia, 1975, AFC 1998/001: SR025; 1 reel-to-reel tape (5 inch)
      - Joel Martin Halpern interviewing in Orasac, Serbia, 1975, AFC 1998/001: SR026; 1 reel-to-reel tape (5 inch)
      - Joel Martin Halpern interviewing in Orasac, Serbia, 1975, AFC 1998/001: SR027; 1 reel-to-reel tape (5 inch)
      - Joel Martin Halpern interviewing in Orasac, Serbia, 1975, AFC 1998/001: SR028; 1 reel-to-reel tape (5 inch)
      - Lao and English text about Serbia, AFC 1998/001: SR029; 1 reel-to-reel tape (5 inch)
    - Audiocassette tapes
      - Halperns in Orasac, 1986, AFC 1998/001: SR030; 1 audiocassette (90 minutes); See also MV04, MV05, MV06, and Box-Folder 1/8
        From documentary depicting the Halperns in Orasac, Serbia, produced by Belgrade Television. Unedited sound track.
      - "Pesme Iz Bosne", AFC 1998/001: SR041; 1 audiocassette (90 minutes)
      - "Music of Serbia / Partisans of Vilnius", AFC 1998/001: SR042; 1 audiocassette (90 minutes)
        From a documentary about the Holocaust in Lithuania.
      - "Traditional Song in South Western Bulgaria: A Geographical Tour," December 1980-February 1981, AFC 1998/001: SR043; Martha Forsyth; 1 audiocassette (60 minutes)
        Recorded in Bulgaria.
      - Traditional Song in South-Western Bulgaria: Songs for Various Functions," December 1980-February 1981, AFC 1998/001: SR044; Martha Forsyth; 1 audiocassette (60 minutes)
      - "The Bistritsa Babi", AFC 1998/001: SR045; 1 audiocassette (90 minutes)
        A group of village women ("grandmothers") from Bistrica, Sofia, Bulgaria. Members of a well-known folksong group which toured the United States.
      - "Ranjenadusa Edin Kulenovi", AFC 1998/001: SR047; 1 audiocassette (60 minutes)
  - Subseries 3: Graphic materials, 1870-1999
    - Bulgaria, late 1800s-1997, Joel Martin Halpern's original black-and-white photograph inventory is filed in the front of this group of photographs; for the typewritten inventory please see Box-Folder 1/3 entitled "Black-and-White Photograph Inventory"
      - Photographs from the Ethnographic Museum in Sofia, Bulgaria, circa late 1800s-early 1900s, circa 1940s-1960s, November 14, 1997, 126 photographic prints, black and white, 5x7 inch; 2 lists (Box-folder 13/156)
        Prints depict Bulgarian subjects from late 19th and early 20th century. Captions handwritten in Bulgarian on verso of each print. Prints appear to be created circa 1940s-1960s. Handwritten list of photograph captions translated from Bulgarian into English by Dr. Elena Mustakova-Possardt, Psychology Dept., State University of West Georgia, Carrolton, Ga. (not in numerical order), dated November 1997. Also a typed list of photograph captions (in numerical order).
        Numbered from #1 to #148. (Some numbers missing.)
      - Slides of the village of Raduil, Bulgaria, September 1996, Joel Martin Halpern; 37 photographic transparencies, color, 35mm slide (Box 13)
        Includes scenes of wool washing and a birthday party. Printed by University Photographic Services, University of Massachusetts, Amherst. Note on media: "Village researched by folklorist Prof Klaus Roth, Univ. of Munich."
      - Photocopies of photographs of Bulgarian and/or Yugoslavian scenes (1), 21 photocopies of photographs; 1 document (Box-folder 13/157)
        Contains the same images as Box-Folder 13/158 but missing photocopies 1-13.
      - Photocopies of photographs of Bulgarian and/or Yugoslavian scenes (2), 34 photocopies of photographs; 1 list; 1 document (Box-folder 13/158)
        Assembled by Joel Martin Halpern to be used in a presentation. Includes captions.
      - Bistrica village costume. Bulgaria, 1 drawing, ink and paint, color (Box-folder 14/163)
    - Yugoslavia and Albania, 1870-1999, Joel Martin Halpern's original color photograph inventory is filed in the front of this group of photographs; for the typewritten inventory, please see Box-Folder 1/4 entitled "Color Photograph Inventory."; Digitized copies of some images are on deposit at the Library of Congress, provided by Joel Martin Halpern (see Box-Folders 14/159 - 14/160 ). Some items provide guides to collection of digitized images presented by Joel Martin Halpern to the Library of Congress.
      - Photocopies of photographs made from negatives at the National Anthropological Archives, Smithsonian Institution National Museum of Natural History, 80 photocopies of photographs; 1 list (Box-folder 14/159)
        Images depict modern Yugoslavian scenes. From negatives. Includes an 8-page list of typed captions in Serbo-Croatian; some captions have a handwritten English translation.
      - Photographs of modern Yugoslavian scenes, 54 photographic prints, color, 3.5x5 inch; 54 photographic negatives, color, 35mm; 1 list (Box-folder 14/160)
        Images in 4 photo rolls depict modern Yugoslavian scenes. Includes photo-identification guide compiled by AFC staff.
      - Photograph of Albanian architecture, 1 photographic print, color, 4x6 inch; 1 list (Box-folder 14/161)
        Includes notes.
      - Photographs of Balkan Music Ensemble in native costume, 2 photographic prints, color, 3.5x5 inch; 2 documents (Box-folder 14/162)
        Includes program and brochures.
      - Photocopies of photographs of Bosnia-Doboj, Zepce, Odzak, Tesanj, Maglaj; Vojvodina, 1930s-1960s, 130 photocopies of photographs (Box-folder 15/164)
      - Photocopies of photographs of former Yugoslavia-Area of Zabaljak, near Mt. Durmitor, Montenegro, 1961, 291 photocopies of photographs (Box-folder 15/165)
      - Photocopies of photographs of former Yugoslavia, 1961-1962, 428 photocopies of photographs (Box-folder 15/166)
      - Photocopies of photographs of former Yugoslavia-Zupca (Bosnia village), 1962, 136 photocopies of photographs (Box-folder 15/167)
      - Photocopies of photographs of former Yugoslavia, August 1962, 47 photocopies of photographs (Box-folder 15/168)
      - Photocopies of photographs of Macedonia-Struga district, 1962, 108 photocopies of photographs (Box-folder 15/169)
      - Photocopies of photographs of former Yugoslavia-Orasac, Summer 1966, 38 photocopies of photographs (Box-folder 15/170)
      - Photocopies of photographs of former Yugoslavia-Orasac and Arandjelovac in Serbia, 1970, 104 photocopies of photographs (Box-folder 15/171)
      - Color plates of Serbian traditional costumes from the Ethnographic Museum in Belgrade, undated, circa 1950s-1990s, 5 plates, color (Box-folder 17/172 (Oversize))
        Mounted on black poster board, bound together with yarn. Images may date from the 1930s. Plates appear to have been printed in the 1950s-1990s.
      - Color plates in Die Serben an der Adria. Leipzig: F.A. Brockhaus, 1870-1878, undated, 9 plates, color (Box-folder 17/174 (Oversize))
        Yugoslavian traditional costume. Bound in portfolio. Booklet covers are imprinted 1870-1878. Plates are undated.
      - Color plates in Stari Zagreb, 12 plates, color (Box-folder 17/175 (Oversize))
        Scenes of Zagreb. Mounted in a portfolio, with table of contents.
      - Black-and-white drawings in Deroko, A. Narodno neimarstvo. Institut za Narodnu Umetnost Beogradskog Univerziteta, 1940, 20 drawings, ink, black and white (Box-folder 17/176 (Oversize))
        Traditional architecture. Collected in a portfolio.
  - Subseries 4: Moving images, 1986-1988
    - Halperns in Orasac, October 27, 1986, AFC 1998/001: MV04; TV Beograd; AFC 1998/001: VT004; 1 videocassette (120 minutes); See also MV05, MV06, SR030, and Box-Folder 1/8
      Documentary depicting the Halperns in Orasac, Serbia, produced by Belgrade Television. Master dub, English audio. Note on media: "Incomplete begins [illegible]."
    - Halpernovi u Orasacu, 1986, AFC 1998/001: MV05; TV Beograd; AFC 1998/001: VT005; 1 videocassette (60 minutes); See also MV04, MV06, SR030, and Box-Folder 1/8
      Documentary depicting the Halperns in Orasac, Serbia, produced by Belgrade Television. Taped from broadcast by Milan Grba in Beta. Notes on media: credits.
    - Slideshow of the making of Halperns in Orasac; with A Serbian Village, January 7, 1988, AFC 1998/001: MV06; AFC 1998/001: VT006; 1 videocassette (120 minutes); See also MV04, MV05, SR030, and Box-Folder 1/8
      Slideshow documenting the making of Halperns in Orasac. Notes on media: "U Mass 01/07/88 JMH + BKH slide + video / A Serbian Village;" and "JMH-BKH Slide Pres. UMass. Audio/Vis."
- Series 2: Southeast Asian materials, 1957-2000
  - Subseries 1: Manuscript materials, 1957-1987, Dates in this series usually refer to publication dates; the collection contains many photocopies of publications, with some originals.
    - Joel Martin Halpern: Unpublished texts, 1957
      - Halpern, Joel Martin. Trip with the Prince. (Prince Phetserath, Viceroy of Laos), 1957, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 18/177)
    - Joel Martin Halpern: Published texts, 1978-1992
      - Brafman, Fred. The Village of the Deep Pond, Ban Xa Phang Meuk, Laos. Edited by James A. Hafner and Joel Martin Halpern. Amherst: International Area Studies Programs, University of Massachusetts: 48 pages, 1978, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 18/178)
      - Brafman, Fred. The Old Man: a Biographical Account of a Lao Villager. Introduced and edited by Joel Martin Halpern and James Hafner. Amherst: International Area Studies Programs, University of Massachusetts: 49 pages, 1979, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 18/179)
      - A Bibliography of Cambodian, Hmong, Lao, and Vietnamese Americans. Edited by Joel Martin Halpern and Lucy Nguyen-Hong-Nhiem. Amherst: Asian Studies Program, University of Massachusetts: 141 pages, 1992, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 18/180)